[
    {
        "question": "A is formed by reversing the digits of B. B is 45 less than A. The sum of the digits of B is 9. What is A?",
        "options": [
            "36",
            "81",
            "54",
            "72"
        ],
        "answer": "72"
    },
    {
        "question": "Square of difference between two numbers is 9 while the sum of squares of those two numbers is 225. What is their product?",
        "options": [
            "108",
            "125",
            "169",
            "96"
        ],
        "answer": "108"
    },
    {
        "question": "4/7 of 2/3 of 5/6 of\u00a0\u00a05/8 of 1008 is",
        "options": [
            "200",
            "144",
            "64",
            "400"
        ],
        "answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "question": "A class eats 2/5 of chocolates on 1stday. On the 2ndday they eat 3/4 of the remainder. How many chocolates were there initially if still 75 chocolates are left?",
        "options": [
            "250",
            "750",
            "500",
            "1000"
        ],
        "answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of two numbers is 5 : 6 and their LCM is 480, then their HCF is?",
        "options": [
            "16",
            "96",
            "12",
            "240"
        ],
        "answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Manoj wants to paste wallpaper on wall of his room. The wall is 4 meters and 50 cm in length and 3 meters and 50 cm in height. But the wall should be covered completely only by square pieces of wallpaper having same size. What is the number of maximum sized wallpaper squares needed to cover the walls completely?",
        "options": [
            "8",
            "15.75",
            "63",
            "12"
        ],
        "answer": "63"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "1/8.485",
            "8.485",
            "1.072",
            "1.060"
        ],
        "answer": "1.060"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is value of [(3 x 3 x 3 x 3 x 3 x 3)6\u00f7 (3 x 3 x 3 x 3)7x 34]?",
        "options": [
            "27",
            "27",
            "3",
            "9",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "274"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be fraction form of 0.2365236523652365\u2026?",
        "options": [
            "2365/10000",
            "2365/9999",
            "1254/9999",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2365/9999"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "3000",
            "9000",
            "6000",
            "3333"
        ],
        "answer": "6000"
    },
    {
        "question": "Resultant price of mixture of golden rice is Rs. 480 per kg. This mixture is made from two varieties of golden rice which are having price of Rs. 420 per kg and Rs. 520 per kg. What should be ratio of quantities of both types of golden rice?",
        "options": [
            "1:3",
            "1:2",
            "2:1",
            "4:1"
        ],
        "answer": "1:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a mixture of 90 L the ratio of acid and water is 2 : 1. If the ratio of acid and water is to be 1 : 2, then the amount of water (in litres) to be added to the mixture is?",
        "options": [
            "20L",
            "40L",
            "90L",
            "100L"
        ],
        "answer": "90L"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ratio of profits of P, Q and R are 8 : 7 : 9 respectively. For what ratio of time periods did they invest if investments are in the ratio 3 : 2 : 5 respectively?",
        "options": [
            "24:14:45",
            "85:45:74",
            "3:2:5",
            "80:75:54"
        ],
        "answer": "80:75:54"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be selling price, if cost price is Rs. 120 and gain is 35%?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 135",
            "Rs. 85",
            "Rs. 155",
            "Rs. 162"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 162"
    },
    {
        "question": "A sold a car to B at a profit of 25%. B incurred loss of 15% while selling the same car to C. A spent Rs. 50000 for this car. At what price did C buy it?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 62500",
            "Rs. 60000",
            "Rs. 53125",
            "Rs. 90000"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 53125"
    },
    {
        "question": "4 members form a group out of total 8 members.(i) In how many ways it is possible to make the group if two particular members must be included.(ii) In how many ways it is possible to make the group if two particular members must not be included?",
        "options": [
            "15 and 360",
            "15 and 15",
            "30 and 360",
            "360 and 360"
        ],
        "answer": "15 and 15"
    },
    {
        "question": "A train 120 m long passes a telegraph post in 6 seconds. Find the speed of the train.",
        "options": [
            "60 km/hr",
            "72.5 km/hr",
            "80 km/hr",
            "72 km/hr"
        ],
        "answer": "72 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question": "A train passes a telegraph post in 8 seconds and a 264 m long bridge in 20 seconds. What is the length of the train",
        "options": [
            "180 m",
            "176 m",
            "164 m",
            "158 m"
        ],
        "answer": "176 m"
    },
    {
        "question": "If ratio of the areas of two squares is 1:4, the ratio of their perimeters is",
        "options": [
            "1:2",
            "1:4",
            "1:6",
            "1:8"
        ],
        "answer": "1:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The perimeter of a square is 48cm. The area of rectangle is 4cm2less than the area of the square. If length of the rectangle is 14cm, then its perimeter is",
        "options": [
            "24cm",
            "48cm",
            "50cm",
            "54cm"
        ],
        "answer": "48cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "An equilateral triangle is described on the diagonal of a square. What is the ratio of the area of the triangle to that of the square?",
        "options": [
            "",
            "2:",
            "",
            "4:"
        ],
        "answer": "3:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The side and one of the diagonals of a rhombus are 13cm and 24cm respectively. The area of the rhombus (in sq.cm.) is",
        "options": [
            "156",
            "240",
            "120",
            "130"
        ],
        "answer": "120"
    },
    {
        "question": "A room is 6m long, 5m broad and 4m high. The maximum length of rod that can be kept in the room is",
        "options": [
            "",
            "",
            "",
            ""
        ],
        "answer": "77m"
    },
    {
        "question": "Average age of A and B is 30 years, that of B and C is 32 years and the average age of C and A is 34 years. The age of C is",
        "options": [
            "33 years",
            "34 years",
            "35 years",
            "36 years"
        ],
        "answer": "36 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average of three numbers is 77. The first number is twice the second and the second number is twice the third. Find the first number.",
        "options": [
            "33",
            "66",
            "77",
            "132"
        ],
        "answer": "132"
    },
    {
        "question": "The average of fifty numbers is 28. If two numbers, namely 25 and 35 are discarded, the average of the remaining numbers is nearly,",
        "options": [
            "29.27",
            "27.92",
            "27.29",
            "29.72"
        ],
        "answer": "27.92"
    },
    {
        "question": "If square root of 5625 is 75, then5625+56.25+0.5625is equal to",
        "options": [
            "9",
            "83.25",
            "82.80",
            "8.325"
        ],
        "answer": "83.25"
    },
    {
        "question": "461+ 462+ 463+ 464+ 465is divisible by",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "5",
            "11",
            "17"
        ],
        "answer": "11"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is value of.1 x .1 x .1 + .02 x .02 x .02.2 x .2 x .2 +\u00a0\u00a0.04 x .04 x .04",
        "options": [
            "0.0125",
            "0.125",
            "0.25",
            "0.5"
        ],
        "answer": "0.125"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a = 4.36, b = 2.39, c = 1.97, then the value of a3-b3-c3-3abc is",
        "options": [
            "3.94",
            "2.39",
            "0",
            "1"
        ],
        "answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a*b = 2a+3b, then the value of 2*3 + 3*4 is",
        "options": [
            "24",
            "31",
            "32",
            "34"
        ],
        "answer": "31"
    },
    {
        "question": "If 12+22+32+\u2026..+ 102= 385, then 32+62+92+\u2026.+302is equal to",
        "options": [
            "3465",
            "2310",
            "1155",
            "770"
        ],
        "answer": "3465"
    },
    {
        "question": "The least of the following 0.2, (.2)2, 0.2, 1\u00f70.2",
        "options": [
            "(.2)",
            "0.2",
            "0.",
            "1\u00f70.2"
        ],
        "answer": "(.2)2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find A:B:C:D when A:B = 2:3 ; B:C = 7:9 ; C:D = 5:7",
        "options": [
            "70 : 105 : 135 : 189",
            "105 : 115 : 236 :189",
            "70 : 124 : 155 : 201",
            "12 : 78 : 256 : 189"
        ],
        "answer": "70 : 105 : 135 : 189"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rs. 20400 was divided in two parts and then invested. One part invested at 6.25% for 8 years yields the same interest as the other part invested at 7% for 5 years. What is the value of smaller part?",
        "options": [
            "9600",
            "8400",
            "10100",
            "6500"
        ],
        "answer": "8400"
    },
    {
        "question": "The population of a city is 50,000 at present. It increases at the rate of 10% per annum. What will be its population 3 yr from now?",
        "options": [
            "67,250",
            "65,550",
            "60,500",
            "66,550"
        ],
        "answer": "66,550"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ramesh sees a thief at a distance of 80 m. Ramesh starts chasing the thief who is running at a speed of 5 m/s. Ramesh is chasing him with a speed of 7 m/s. How much distance does the thief covers before Ramesh catches him?",
        "options": [
            "130 m",
            "50 m",
            "100 m",
            "200 m"
        ],
        "answer": "200 m"
    },
    {
        "question": "12 years ago, age of P was 3 times the age of Q. After 12 years, ratio of ages of Q to P will be 2:3. What is the present age of P?",
        "options": [
            "54 years",
            "36 years",
            "24 years",
            "144 years"
        ],
        "answer": "36 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "Average age of a family of 4 members was 19 years, 4 years back. Birth of a new child kept the average age of the family same even today. How old is the child today?",
        "options": [
            "4 years",
            "1 year",
            "2 years",
            "3 years"
        ],
        "answer": "3 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "A can work 5 times faster than B and takes 60 days less than B to complete the work. In how many days does A and B individually can complete the work?",
        "options": [
            "A = 20 days; B = 100 days",
            "A = 20 days; B = 80 days",
            "A = 15 days; B = 75 days",
            "A = 10 days; B = 50 days"
        ],
        "answer": "A = 15 days; B = 75 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "If 3 men can do a work in 2 days and 4 boys can do the same work in 6 days, then in how many days will the same work be completed by 8 men and 8 boys?",
        "options": [
            "2 days",
            "3/5 Days",
            "1.5 Days",
            "3/4 Days"
        ],
        "answer": "3/5 Days"
    },
    {
        "question": "A and B took a job for Rs. 7200. A alone can do it in 12 days. B alone can do it in 16 days. They completed the work in 6 days with the help of C. Find the share of C.",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 1200",
            "Rs. 900",
            "Rs. 800",
            "Rs. 600"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 900"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pipe P can fill a tank in 38 hours. Pipe Q alone can fill it in 19 hours. Pipe R can empty the full tank in 133 hours. If all the pipes are opened together, how much time will be needed to make the tank full?",
        "options": [
            "28 hours",
            "95 hours",
            "19 hours",
            "14 hours"
        ],
        "answer": "14 hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "A train is 31m long. It passes a platform which is 175 m long. What is the distance covered by the train in passing the platform?",
        "options": [
            "206 m",
            "144 m",
            "175/31 m",
            "Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "answer": "206 m"
    },
    {
        "question": "With stoppage, the speed of a train is 36 km/hr. However without stoppage, it is 40 km/hr. Find out for how many minutes does the train stop per hour?",
        "options": [
            "6 minutes",
            "8 minutes",
            "10 minutes",
            "4 minutes"
        ],
        "answer": "6 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "A river flows at speed of 6 km/hr. Surendra swims downstream for some distance in just 12 hours. But he takes 18 hours to return the same distance upstream. How fast is Surendra in still water?",
        "options": [
            "30 km/hr",
            "24 km/hr",
            "12 km/hr",
            "36 km/hr"
        ],
        "answer": "30 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much will be the average of the squares of natural numbers from 1 to 35?",
        "options": [
            "612.5",
            "1225",
            "426",
            "324"
        ],
        "answer": "426"
    },
    {
        "question": "How old will be the Raju if ratio of his age and one of his twin grandsons\u2019 is 11:2 and average age of his and his both grandsons is 50 years?",
        "options": [
            "72 years",
            "110 years",
            "75 years",
            "150 years"
        ],
        "answer": "110 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ramesh and Suresh start cleaning a pool together. They do it in 26 days but for the last 6 days only Ramesh was working.\u00a0\u00a0When Suresh works alone, in how much time will he completely clean the pool, if Ramesh and Suresh together can clean the pool in 24 days?",
        "options": [
            "36 days",
            "72 days",
            "52 days",
            "13 days"
        ],
        "answer": "72 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "A box has 6 black, 4 red, 2 white and 3 blue shirts. When 2 shirts are picked randomly, what is the probability that either both are white or both are blue?",
        "options": [
            "4/105",
            "1/35",
            "1/105",
            "1/15"
        ],
        "answer": "4/105"
    },
    {
        "question": "Summation of 5 consecutive numbers is found out to be 335. If we add the largest and smallest number what will we get?",
        "options": [
            "134",
            "150",
            "174",
            "226"
        ],
        "answer": "134"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is largest fraction amongst 5/8, 3/7, 2/9,\u00a0\u00a04/5?",
        "options": [
            "3/7",
            "5/8",
            "4/5",
            "All are equal"
        ],
        "answer": "4/5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rational numbers lie between 1/3 and\u00a0\u00a04/5 ?",
        "options": [
            "21/42  and 9/50",
            "693/1000 and 22/30",
            "1/6 and 5/6",
            "1/2 and 1/4"
        ],
        "answer": "693/1000 and 22/30"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is HCF of\u00a0\u00a036/75, 48/150 , 72/135?",
        "options": [
            "12/1350",
            "150/36",
            "1350/36",
            "72/225"
        ],
        "answer": "12/1350"
    },
    {
        "question": "What largest number will divide 47, 35 and 27 leaving same remainder in each case? What will be the common remainder?",
        "options": [
            "9, 1",
            "1, 9",
            "4, 3",
            "3, 4"
        ],
        "answer": "4, 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ajay had some books in his library. He tried packing them in bags in various ways. While packing 85 books in each bag, 9 bags were not filled completely. Also, while packing 58 books in each bag, 13 bags were not enough to pack all the books. But in the end he was able to pack the books in M bags each having M books. How many books did Ajay have?",
        "options": [
            "765",
            "812",
            "729",
            "784"
        ],
        "answer": "784"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is value of60.004096?",
        "options": [
            "0.4",
            "4",
            "0.04",
            "64"
        ],
        "answer": "0.4"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a class, there are some girls and boys. One day, 30 boys leave the class, so there were 4 girls for each boy. After some time, on the same day, 175 girls leave the class. Then, there were 2 boys for each girl. How much would be double the number of boys originally present in the class?",
        "options": [
            "225",
            "193",
            "160",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "160"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be value of c, if a(a+b+c) = 85; b(a+b+c) = 96; c(a+b+c) = 108?",
        "options": [
            "108/96",
            "108/11",
            "108/17",
            "108/85"
        ],
        "answer": "108/17"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "963",
            "1800",
            "2400",
            "2700"
        ],
        "answer": "2400"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a set of 30 game cards, 17 are white and rest are green. 4 white and 5 green are marked IMPORTANT. If a card is chosen randomly from this set, what is the possibility of choosing a green card or an \u2018IMPORTANT\u2019 card?",
        "options": [
            "13/30",
            "22/30",
            "17/30",
            "9/13"
        ],
        "answer": "17/30"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much milk should be added in a milk solution to make milk quantity in it 75%, if 80 L of milk solution has 45% milk in it?",
        "options": [
            "96 litres",
            "75 litres",
            "30 litres",
            "110 litres"
        ],
        "answer": "96 litres"
    },
    {
        "question": "A mixture of two food items has a salt to sugar ratio of 7 : 32. The ratio of salt to sugar is 2 : 11 and 5 : 21, in the two individual types of food items. In what proportion are the 2 food items mixed?",
        "options": [
            "10 : 321",
            "1 : 2",
            "7 : 32",
            "2 : 1"
        ],
        "answer": "1 : 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "P and Q invested in a hotel with Rs. 35000 and Rs. 25000 respectively.\u00a0\u00a0R comes along and puts a condition that each must share the profit equally. To do so, he gives Rs. 400000 to P and Q to share between them. In what ratio do A and B respectively share the money given by C?",
        "options": [
            "13:7",
            "7:13",
            "7:5",
            "5:7"
        ],
        "answer": "7:13"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rambabu sells paper planes at the rate of 20 planes for Re. 1. If he gets profit of 20%, how many planes did he buy in 1 rupee?",
        "options": [
            "16",
            "40",
            "24",
            "36"
        ],
        "answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rohit got profit of 11\u00bd% by selling his old car. However he realized that had he sold it for Rs. 8100 more, his profit would be 38.5%. At what price did he buy the car?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 44500",
            "Rs. 55000",
            "Rs. 41000",
            "Rs. 30000"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 30000"
    },
    {
        "question": "There are 35 people in a group. There are 12 school girls, 10 school boys, 5 senior citizens and 8 babies in the group. The organizer of the group wants to select a school girl or a school boy as leader of the group. In how many ways can he do so?",
        "options": [
            "22",
            "1/2",
            "13",
            "35"
        ],
        "answer": "22"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of numbers of girls and boys participating in sports of a school is 4:5. If the number of girls is 212, determine the number of boys participating in the sports.",
        "options": [
            "256",
            "265",
            "251",
            "263"
        ],
        "answer": "265"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of market prices of wheat and paddy is 2:3 and the ratio of quantities consumed in a family is 5:4. Find the ratio of expenditure of wheat and paddy.",
        "options": [
            "6:5",
            "5:6",
            "1:1",
            "8:15"
        ],
        "answer": "5:6"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cistern is normally filled with water in 10 hours but takes 5 hours longer to fill because of a leak in its bottom. If the cistern is full, the leak will empty the cistern in",
        "options": [
            "20 hours",
            "40 hours",
            "50 hours",
            "30 hours"
        ],
        "answer": "30 hours"
    },
    {
        "question": "A and B can finish a piece of work in 30 days, B and C can finish it in 15 days, C and A in 10 days. Time taken by them together to do this work is?",
        "options": [
            "5 days",
            "2(1/2) days",
            "7(1/2) days",
            "10 days"
        ],
        "answer": "10 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "A can do 1/4thpart of work in 10 days and B can do 40% work in 40 days\u00a0\u00a0and C can do 1/3rdof the work in 13 days. Who will complete the work first?",
        "options": [
            "A",
            "B",
            "C",
            "A and C both"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "A takes twice as much time as B or thrice as much time as C to finish a piece of work; working together they can finish the work in 2 days. B can do the work alone in",
        "options": [
            "12 days",
            "4 days",
            "8 days",
            "6 days"
        ],
        "answer": "6 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "A circular wire of radius 21cm is cut and bent to form in the form of a rectangle whose sides are in the ratio of 6:5. Assuming, \u03a0 = 22/7, the area enclosed by the rectangle is",
        "options": [
            "540 cm",
            "1080 cm",
            "2160 cm",
            "4320 cm"
        ],
        "answer": "1080 cm2"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the areas of the three adjacent faces of a cuboidal box are 120cm2, 72cm2and 60cm2respectively, find the volume of the box.",
        "options": [
            "7200 cm",
            "720 cm",
            "864 cm",
            "(72)"
        ],
        "answer": "720 cm3"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of coins of radius 0.75 cm and thickness 0.2 cm to be melted to make a right circular cylinder of height 8 cm and base radius 3 cm is",
        "options": [
            "640",
            "460",
            "500",
            "600"
        ],
        "answer": "640"
    },
    {
        "question": "The area of the base of a right circular cone is 154cm2and its height is 14cm. Taking \u03c0 = 22/7, the curved surface of the cone is",
        "options": [
            "154 x",
            "154 x",
            "11 cm",
            "5324 cm"
        ],
        "answer": "154 x5cm2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The L.C.M. of two numbers is 14560 and their H.C.F. is 13. If one of them is 416, the other is",
        "options": [
            "460",
            "455",
            "450",
            "445"
        ],
        "answer": "455"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sum of two numbers is 156 and their HCF is 13. The numbers of such number pairs is",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "5",
            "4",
            "3"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a number is divided by 893 the remainder is 193. What will be the remainder when it is divided by 47?",
        "options": [
            "19",
            "5",
            "33",
            "23"
        ],
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the least number which when divided by the numbers 3, 5, 6, 8, 10 and 12 leaves in each case a remainder 2 but which when divided by 13 leaves no remainder?",
        "options": [
            "312",
            "962",
            "1586",
            "1562"
        ],
        "answer": "1586"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "15",
            "25",
            "45",
            "35"
        ],
        "answer": "45"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integer is 10 more than its one-third part. The integer is",
        "options": [
            "15",
            "12",
            "18",
            "25"
        ],
        "answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "question": "The greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40, 75 is",
        "options": [
            "600",
            "9000",
            "9600",
            "9400"
        ],
        "answer": "9600"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is value of ? in 0.9637 + ? + 38.9+22.257 = 91.1207",
        "options": [
            "40",
            "25",
            "29",
            "35"
        ],
        "answer": "29"
    },
    {
        "question": "Paper charge is Rs. 60 per kg. How much expenditure would be there to cover a cube of edge 10m with a paper, if one kg of paper covers 20 sq.m. area?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 2250",
            "Rs. 3600",
            "Rs. 2700",
            "Rs. 1800"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 1800"
    },
    {
        "question": "A poster is on top of a building. Rajesh is standing on the ground at a distance of 50 m from the building. The angles of elevation to the top of the poster and bottom of the poster are 45\u00b0 and 30\u00b0 respectively. What is the height of the poster?",
        "options": [
            "50(",
            "50",
            "25/",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "50(3- 1)/3m"
    },
    {
        "question": "54 toymakers can prepare 36 toys per day. Ajay wants 416 toys. How many toymakers should he employ to get the job done in 16 days?",
        "options": [
            "43",
            "39",
            "16",
            "24"
        ],
        "answer": "39"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kabir paid Rs. 9600 as interest on a loan he took 5 years ago at 16% rate of simple interest. What was the amount he took as loan?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 16400",
            "Rs. 12000",
            "Rs. 12500",
            "Rs. 18000"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 12000"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sam borrowed some money from his friend at simple interest of 6% per annum. He returned his friend Rs. 15600. After how much time did Sam return the money if he borrowed Rs. 12000?",
        "options": [
            "8 years",
            "2.5 years",
            "5 years",
            "3.5 years"
        ],
        "answer": "5 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "19.399 + 10.33 + 7.82 + 3.111 = ?",
        "options": [
            "40.66",
            "40.65",
            "90.856",
            "40.566"
        ],
        "answer": "40.66"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cistern has two taps attached to it. Tap B can empty the cistern in 45 minutes. But Tap A can fill the cistern in just 30 minutes. Rohit started both taps unknowingly but realized his mistake after 30 minutes. He immediately closed Tap B. Now after this, in how much time will the cistern be filled?",
        "options": [
            "30 minutes",
            "45 minutes",
            "15 minutes",
            "20 minutes"
        ],
        "answer": "20 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ramesh has a metal cube. He paints all sides of the cube with green color. He divides the cube into smaller cubes of volume 1 cu.m. each. How many of these smaller cubes will not have green color on even one of its sides if the volume of larger cube is 27 cu.m.?",
        "options": [
            "9",
            "1",
            "0",
            "3"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "20 girls can paint a house in 15 days. But the same house can be painted in just 10 days by 15 boys. If 10 boys and 10 girls are asked to work together, then in how many days will they complete the painting starting from scratch?",
        "options": [
            "30 minutes",
            "45 minutes",
            "15 minutes",
            "10 days"
        ],
        "answer": "10 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Jaya divided surface area of a sphere by the sphere\u2019s volume, she got the answer as 1/18 cm. What is the radius of the sphere?",
        "options": [
            "24 cm",
            "6 cm",
            "54 cm",
            "4.5 cm"
        ],
        "answer": "54 cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "James hired some workers to build his house in 20 days. But on the day of starting of the construction, 12 men did not come. Rest of the people then built the entire house in 32 days. How many workers had he initially hired?",
        "options": [
            "64",
            "48",
            "32",
            "24"
        ],
        "answer": "32"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dean has a cardboard box whose length, breadth and height are in the ratio 1:2:3. He makes a new box such that the length, breadth and height got increased by 100%, 200% and 200% respectively. How much less is volume of old box than the new box?",
        "options": [
            "12 times less",
            "16 times less",
            "17 times less",
            "24 times less"
        ],
        "answer": "17 times less"
    },
    {
        "question": "If value of28is approximately 5.2915, then value of7/4is approximately",
        "options": [
            "1.2000",
            "0.5687",
            "1.3228",
            "1.4652"
        ],
        "answer": "1.3228"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be value of 1/0.0004659 if, 1/4.659 = .2146?",
        "options": [
            "214.6",
            "2146",
            "2.146",
            "21.46"
        ],
        "answer": "2146"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be value of (8.5 x 5.8+ 8.5 x 4.2)/(1.7 x 7.6 - 1.7 x 6.6) ?",
        "options": [
            "13.56",
            "5.25",
            "10",
            "50"
        ],
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be value of46.7856if, (684)2= 467856?",
        "options": [
            "6.84",
            "0.0684",
            "0.684",
            "0.000684"
        ],
        "answer": "6.84"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sarang invested some money in HDFC at 3% rate of interest. What would be the corresponding simple interest if after 2 years, Sarang got Rs. 101.50 as compound interest?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 1015",
            "Rs. 125",
            "Rs. 100",
            "Rs. 150"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 100"
    },
    {
        "question": "LCM of two numbers is 138. But their GCD is 23. The numbers are in a ratio 1:6. Which is the largest number amongst the two?",
        "options": [
            "46",
            "138",
            "69",
            "23"
        ],
        "answer": "138"
    },
    {
        "question": "A steel vessel has a base of length 60 cm and breadth 30 cm. Water is poured in the vessel. A cubical steel box having edge of 30 cm is immersed completely in the vessel. How much will the water rise?",
        "options": [
            "7.5 cm rise",
            "10 cm rise",
            "15 cm rise",
            "30 cm rise"
        ],
        "answer": "15 cm rise"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "14(1/10)",
            "13(1/5)",
            "13/30",
            "14(1/30)"
        ],
        "answer": "14(1/30)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ramesh has a rectangular wooden block. P, Q and R are the areas of the three adjacent and contiguous faces of the block. If we denote its volume by S, then which of the following is true for sure?",
        "options": [
            "S = 2(P+Q+R)",
            "",
            "S",
            "S"
        ],
        "answer": "S2= PQR"
    },
    {
        "question": "Raju has a cone, a hemisphere and a cylinder. They have the same height. Raju immerses them completely in a bucket full of water. What will be ratio of volume of cylinder to cone to hemisphere, if they also have same bases?",
        "options": [
            "1:2:3",
            "3:1:2",
            "2:1:3",
            "1:1:1"
        ],
        "answer": "3:1:2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sam has a solid metal ball with diameter 6cm. He melts it and uses the material for making a solid cylinder. If the diameter of the cylinder is same as the ball, what would its height be?",
        "options": [
            "4 cm",
            "4.5 cm",
            "6 cm",
            "8 cm"
        ],
        "answer": "4 cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "A small library is started by Prakash and John. Prakash invests Rs. 2000 and John Rs. 5000 for 9 and 7 months respectively. In what ratio will John and Prakash share the profit of Rs. 1100?",
        "options": [
            "2:3",
            "21:27",
            "35:18",
            "45:56"
        ],
        "answer": "35:18"
    },
    {
        "question": "George gets a discount of 30% and then 20% on his food bill of Rs. 1250. What is the total discount he got?",
        "options": [
            "44%",
            "55%",
            "52%",
            "25%"
        ],
        "answer": "44%"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shamik had invested same amount of sums at simple as well as compound interest. The time period of both the sums was 2 years and rate of interest too was same 4% per annum. At the end, he found a difference of Rs. 50 in both the interests received. What were the sums invested?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 32550",
            "Rs. 35750",
            "Rs. 30000",
            "Rs. 31250"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 31250"
    },
    {
        "question": "Simran gets a discount of 25% on Rs. 3600 oven. Since she pays cash, she gets additional 2% discount too. How much does she pay?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 2864",
            "Rs. 2468",
            "Rs. 2548",
            "Rs. 2646"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 2646"
    },
    {
        "question": "Michel can swim in still water at the rate of 6km per hour. After swimming in a stream, she realized that she takes twice the time to go upstream as she takes to go downstream. What is speed of the current?",
        "options": [
            "2.25 km/hr",
            "2 km/hr",
            "4 km/hr",
            "1.5 km/hr"
        ],
        "answer": "2 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question": "Greatest Common Divisor of two numbers is 8 while their Least Common Multiple is 144. Find the other number if one number is 16.",
        "options": [
            "108",
            "96",
            "72",
            "36"
        ],
        "answer": "72"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the value of\u00a0\u00a01 x 0.3 x 0.01 x 0.003?",
        "options": [
            "0.000009",
            "0.000027",
            "0.00009",
            "0.00003"
        ],
        "answer": "0.000009"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is value of (36)\u2159?",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "",
            "1",
            ""
        ],
        "answer": "36"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many zeroes are there in 200010?",
        "options": [
            "10",
            "30",
            "20",
            "15"
        ],
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "question": "40% of greater number is equal to 60% of the smaller. If their sum is 150, then the greater number is",
        "options": [
            "70",
            "80",
            "90",
            "60"
        ],
        "answer": "90"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two numbers are less than a third number by 30% and 37% respectively. How much percent is the second number less than the first?",
        "options": [
            "7%",
            "10%",
            "4%",
            "3%"
        ],
        "answer": "10%"
    },
    {
        "question": "The difference between simple and compound interest on a certain sum of money for 2 years at 4 percent per annum is Re.1. The sum of money is",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 600",
            "Rs. 625",
            "Rs. 560",
            "Rs. 650"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 625"
    },
    {
        "question": "A sum of money invested at compound interest amounts to Rs. 800 in 3 years and to Rs. 840 in 4 years. The rate of interest per annum is",
        "options": [
            "2(1/2)%",
            "4%",
            "5%",
            "6(2/3)%"
        ],
        "answer": "5%"
    },
    {
        "question": "If simple interest on a certain sum for 15 months at 7(1/2) % per annum exceeds the simple interest on the same sum for 8 months at 12(1/2)% per annum by Rs. 32.50, then the sum (in Rs.) is",
        "options": [
            "312",
            "312.50",
            "3120",
            "3120.50"
        ],
        "answer": "3120"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 4 years the simple interest on certain sum of money is 9/25 of the principal. The annual rate of interest is",
        "options": [
            "4%",
            "4(1/2)%",
            "9%",
            "10%"
        ],
        "answer": "9%"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "5",
            "4",
            "3"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is greatest among the following numbers?22,7, 23,5",
        "options": [
            "",
            "2",
            "2",
            ""
        ],
        "answer": "23"
    },
    {
        "question": "Simplify:0.72 x 0.72 x 0.72 - 0.39 x 0.39 x 0.390.72 x 0.72 + 0.72 x 0.39 + 0.39 x 0.39",
        "options": [
            "0.333",
            "0.33",
            "0.3333",
            "0.3334"
        ],
        "answer": "0.33"
    },
    {
        "question": "The product of two positive numbers is 4752 and their ratio is 11:12. The smaller of these numbers is",
        "options": [
            "72",
            "60",
            "66",
            "75"
        ],
        "answer": "66"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sum of squares of two numbers is 145. If square root of one number is 3, find the other number.",
        "options": [
            "136",
            "9",
            "64",
            "8"
        ],
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a person sells a \u2018sari\u2019 for Rs. 5200, making a profit of 30%, then the cost price of the sari is",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 4420",
            "Rs. 4000",
            "Rs. 3900",
            "Rs. 3800"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 4000"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of cost price and selling price is 4:5. The profit percent is",
        "options": [
            "10%",
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "30%"
        ],
        "answer": "25%"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two bicycles were sold for Rs. 3990 each, gaining 5% on one and losing 5% on the other. The gain or loss percent on the whole transaction is",
        "options": [
            "Neither gain nor loss",
            "2.5% gain",
            "2.5% loss",
            "0.25% loss"
        ],
        "answer": "0.25% loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "If selling price of 40 articles is equal to cost price of 50 articles, the loss or gain percent is",
        "options": [
            "25% loss",
            "20% loss",
            "25% gain",
            "20% gain"
        ],
        "answer": "25% gain"
    },
    {
        "question": "If x:y = 3:4, then (7x+3y):(7x-3y) is equal to",
        "options": [
            "5:2",
            "4:3",
            "11:3",
            "37:19"
        ],
        "answer": "11:3"
    },
    {
        "question": "On exchanging the digits in unit\u2019s and ten\u2019s place, the difference between original and new numbers becomes 27. The digit in the unit's place is 2 times the digit in the hundred's place. The digit in the ten\u2019s place is 3 times the digit in the hundred\u2019s place. What is 75% of the original number?",
        "options": [
            "99",
            "369",
            "297",
            "396"
        ],
        "answer": "297"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convert 0.88into vulgar fraction",
        "options": [
            "80/99",
            "44/45",
            "22/25",
            "8/9"
        ],
        "answer": "8/9"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "16",
            "7",
            "99/64",
            "32/25"
        ],
        "answer": "32/25"
    },
    {
        "question": "What least possible 4-digit number, when divided by 12, 16, 18 and 20 leaves 21 as remainder?",
        "options": [
            "36",
            "133",
            "144",
            "1461"
        ],
        "answer": "1461"
    },
    {
        "question": "3 birds fly along the circumference of a jungle. They complete one round in 27 minutes, 45 minutes and 63 minutes respectively. Since they start together, when will they meet again at the starting position?",
        "options": [
            "945 minutes",
            "126 minutes",
            "135 minutes",
            "9 hours"
        ],
        "answer": "945 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be least number of marbles with Rohit if he can arrange them in rows of 18, 10 and 15 marbles each as well as make a perfect solid square out of all the marbles?",
        "options": [
            "133",
            "43",
            "90",
            "900"
        ],
        "answer": "900"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "options": [
            "7.48\u2026.",
            "7",
            "8",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find value of\u00a0\u00a01/(25-18), if2= 1.414?",
        "options": [
            "1. 320",
            "1.010",
            "7",
            "0.7"
        ],
        "answer": "1. 320"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find value of a3+ b3+ 3ab, when value of a+b = 1?",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "-1",
            "1/(3ab)",
            "1/(a-b)"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be fraction form of 0.3523?",
        "options": [
            "3488/9900",
            "3523/9900",
            "3523/10000",
            "3488/10000"
        ],
        "answer": "3488/9900"
    },
    {
        "question": "Add 17.499, 17.85 and 36.333",
        "options": [
            "51.909",
            "52.68",
            "53.017",
            "52.15"
        ],
        "answer": "52.683"
    },
    {
        "question": "On rolling a dice 2 times, the sum of 2 numbers that appear on the uppermost face is 8. What is the probability that the first throw of dice yields 4?",
        "options": [
            "2/36",
            "1/36",
            "1/6",
            "1/5"
        ],
        "answer": "1/36"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ramesh mixes 60 litres of Type-1 acid with some litres of Type-2 acid. Type-1 acid rate is Rs. 32 per litre while Type-2 rate is Rs. 23 per litre. Ramesh sells this acid-mix at rate Rs. 28 per litre. How much Type-2 acid is needed to make it a no profit no loss transaction?",
        "options": [
            "48 litres",
            "36 litres",
            "24 litres",
            "50 litres"
        ],
        "answer": "48 litres"
    },
    {
        "question": "M invests Rs. 4000 in coaching classes. After 3 months N comes along with Rs. 8000. P comes in with Rs. 20000. The classes earn a profit of Rs. 112000 at the end of the year. If profits of M, N and Pare in ratio of 6:9:5, for how many months was P involved?",
        "options": [
            "5 months",
            "6 months",
            "2 months",
            "3 months"
        ],
        "answer": "2 months"
    },
    {
        "question": "P, Q and R start a hotel. Q and R invest equally but P invests one-fifth of the total investment amount. On getting profit of Rs. 225000, how much would be difference between profit of P and R?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 90000",
            "Rs. 45000",
            "Rs. 71000",
            "Rs. 112500"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 45000"
    },
    {
        "question": "Simran bought pet food worth Rs. 56000. She then sold 1/3rdof it incurring a loss of 40%. What profit she must earn on rest of the supplies to nullify this loss?",
        "options": [
            "25%",
            "20%",
            "45%",
            "50%"
        ],
        "answer": "20%"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without repetition, using digits 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8 and 0, how many numbers can be made which lie between 500 and 1000?",
        "options": [
            "70",
            "147",
            "60",
            "90"
        ],
        "answer": "90"
    }
]